<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quotes on Nathanial L. McConnell</title>
    <link>http://www.nmcconnell.com/quote/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Quotes on Nathanial L. McConnell</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 11:20:39 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.nmcconnell.com/quote/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>To laugh often and much; to win the respect of intelligent people and the affection of children; to earn the appreciation of honest critics and endure the betrayal of false friends; to appreciate beauty, to find the best in others; to leave the world a little better; whether by a healthy child, a garden patch, or a redeemed social condition; to know even one life has breathed easier because you have lived. This is the meaning of success.</title>
      <link>http://www.nmcconnell.com/quote/to-laugh-often-and-much-to-win-the-respect-of-intelligent-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 11:20:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nmcconnell.com/quote/to-laugh-often-and-much-to-win-the-respect-of-intelligent-people/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;ve seen things you people wouldn&#39;t believe. Attack ships on fire off the shoulder of Orion. I watched C-beams glitter in the dark near the Tannhauser gate. All those moments will be lost in time... like tears in rain... Time to die.</title>
      <link>http://www.nmcconnell.com/quote/ive-seen-things-you-people-wouldnt-believe-attack-ships-on-fire/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 11:20:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nmcconnell.com/quote/ive-seen-things-you-people-wouldnt-believe-attack-ships-on-fire/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In its time, this, his house, had been a place of great souls and great ambition, where all commonplace debate had been banned. If you wanted to talk politics or tittle-tattle you went to the coffee house; if you wanted commerce, to the Exchange. Here only miracles. Here, only the rising of spirit. And yes, love if it was pertinent (which it was so often); and sometimes bloodletting. But never the prosaic, never the trivial. Here the man who brought the strangest tale was the most welcome. Here every excess was celebrated if it brought visions, and every vision analyzed for the hints it held to the nature of the Everlasting.</title>
      <link>http://www.nmcconnell.com/quote/in-its-time-this-his-house-had-been-a-place-of-great-souls-and-great-ambition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 11:20:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nmcconnell.com/quote/in-its-time-this-his-house-had-been-a-place-of-great-souls-and-great-ambition/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sometimes the right thing feels all wring until it is over and done with.</title>
      <link>http://www.nmcconnell.com/quote/sometimes-the-right-thing-feels-all-wring-until-it-is-over-and-done-with/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 11:20:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nmcconnell.com/quote/sometimes-the-right-thing-feels-all-wring-until-it-is-over-and-done-with/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And while it is true I am a supergenius with a robotic house and a rock-climbing tree, I am not perfect. No, really. I&#39;m not! I&#39;ll pause to let the disillusioned stop crying. It&#39;s sad when heroes die.</title>
      <link>http://www.nmcconnell.com/quote/and-while-it-is-true-i-am-a-supergenius-with-a-robotic-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 11:19:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nmcconnell.com/quote/and-while-it-is-true-i-am-a-supergenius-with-a-robotic-house/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The most authentic thing about us is our capacity to create, to overcome, to endure, to transform, to love and to be greater than our suffering.</title>
      <link>http://www.nmcconnell.com/quote/the-most-authentic-thing-about-us-is-our-capacity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 23:02:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nmcconnell.com/quote/the-most-authentic-thing-about-us-is-our-capacity/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>