<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Code on Nathanial L. McConnell</title>
    <link>http://www.nmcconnell.com/tags/code/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Code on Nathanial L. McConnell</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.nmcconnell.com/tags/code/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Disciples of Code: Decoded, Part 1 -- Code</title>
      <link>http://www.nmcconnell.com/post/disciples-of-code-decoded-part-1-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nmcconnell.com/post/disciples-of-code-decoded-part-1-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I say &amp;lsquo;code&amp;rsquo;, you say &amp;lsquo;program&amp;rsquo;. He says &amp;lsquo;script&amp;rsquo;, she says &amp;lsquo;app&amp;rsquo;. Does it matter? Putting aside the many technical definitions and nuances, in practice these terms are nearly synonymous — at least to a general audience. What we&amp;rsquo;re really talking about is machine language, or a way of communicating with machines (e.g., computers) by combining a set of symbols, words, and statements according to certain predefined rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;aside class=&#34;quote pullquote float-right&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;pullquote-right-textbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p class=&#34;pullquote-text text-right first-word&#34;&gt;Communication&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p class=&#34;pullquote-text text-justify remaining-words&#34;&gt;is more than just words, communication is architecture, because of course it is quite obvious that a house which would be built without that will, that desire to communicate, would not look the way your house looks today.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p class=&#34;pullquote-text text-right by&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.officialpoe.com&#34;&gt;Poe (singer)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does this sound familiar? It should. It is identical to the way in which we learn any human language. Code is simply a machine language. While some human languages are moire difficult to learn than others, some machine languages involve trickier grammar or more complex syntax. The driving purpose for learning in both cases is {&amp;rdquo; whether the language learner can create something that makes sense to others &amp;ldquo;}.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Machine languages differ from human languages in many important ways. Speaking and listening aren&amp;rsquo;t often a crucial part of machine languages, but they are vital to human languages; speaking code is not usually performative. Human languages tend to be chronological and have a structural basis at the sentence level. Machine languages don&amp;rsquo;t require strict chronologies, and often encourage using conditional structures to branch off from the linear path — perhaps, infinitely.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>